The Magic Lantern is an instrument
fo the projection of painted images
usually on glass, wall or screen
intentionally prepared in a dark room
with a closed box
containing a candle,
the light of which is filtered
through a hole with a lens.
The most ancient description of
a Magic Lantern dates back to 1646,
when the Jesuit priest Atanasius
Kircher included it in his book
Ars Magna Lucis et Umbrae.
The Magic Lantern could be used
for educational purposes.
It could show places, monuments,
objects, plants, animals
that no-one had ever seen before with
a more impressive result than print.
The Magic Lantern, could be used
also to project fantastical images
as a tool for conferences and sermons,
such as damned souls among flames
and blessed souls in paradise.
At first with the Magic Lantern only
one image at a time was projected
but slowly thanks to other inventions,
in particularly Muscherboek's one,
it was possible to multiply the images
and make them move.
It's not rare to find in the still
existing magic lanterns
true and fantastical images together:
real and fantastical animals,
such as elephants with dragons,
far-away and imaginary places.
Eventually the invention
of photography,
especially by Nicéphore Niépce, paved
the way for further developments.
If he had found the way to have
before his lens a series of frames
he could've reproduced reality.
This will be the Lumière brothers'
winning idea.
In the Recherche, Proust talks about
a state-of-the-art Lantern
which through superimposed panes
gave the illusion of movement,
showing the traitor Golo riding
towards Geneviève's castle.
The Magic Lantern show is the most
direct ancestor of film screenings,
which is nothing but the projection
of photos instead of drawn panes,
at such a speed that gives
the illusion of movement.
The Lantern is the pre-film device
which most reassembles a film show.
"Wilhelm, what is the world
for our heart without love?
It's like a magic lantern without light!
But as soon as you introduce the lamp,
the most beautiful images appear
on the white wall..."
The Sorrows of Young Werther, Goethe