#Happy and blissful
#from great love
#cuckolded by great love
Blocked! You cannot go beyond.
But we must find the way out.
Be we...
in our conscious life
with as much intellingence
as imagination...
we must organize
at best our defence.
I think that...
Banca di Roma...
could be an excellent protection.
Sorry, but the money?
I don't deal with financial issues,
but with psychological problems.
Banca di Roma takes care
of everything else.
Follow my advice and your night
anxiety will disappear.
I like to think I have followed
a good piece of advice.
And from now on I hope
my nights will be peaceful.
I wish you the same.
Good night!
- Gabriella, pleased to meet you.
- They have 11 fruit tastes.
Some customers would like
tuna and onion taste.
But I don't think it's a good idea.
Two hemispheres, the first tastes like
peach, the other one like apricot.
It's a matter of tastes.
The lover chooses...
Don't move, darling!
..bites...
..chews...
It's all good stuff.
Once he gets excited, he feels...
We are planning to add some drugs.
There are three screenings.
Come back later.
The change?
And yet...
You are so pretty!
I've been wanting to meet you
for so long.
Me too.
You are so elegant!
"What's the meaning of the girl
from the spring?
"An offer of purity?
Of warmth to the protagonist?
"Of all your story's overabundant
symbols, this is the worst...
"filled with..."