Hello boys,
are we in trouble?
The usual financial problems?
There isn't a penny left?
Even worse, sex problems?
Don't panic, there's Mandrake.
If I touch it twice
your stick will stand up again.
Michela, Daniela
come and see Marcello!
No, thanks, go to sleep.
Good night.
He keeps on looking.
You see, the film is...
I really want to make this film.
I postponed the shoot
for two weeks because...
Mezzabotta!
It's difficult to clarify this feeling.
It's as if for some time things...
looked at me in a strange way.
OK, snails and Valpolicella.
- Giulio, please let me take a snap.
- It isn't possible.
Why are you giving him
all that money?
If you want information,
I'm always here.
- You're insulting me.
- What's wrong?
Let me come here more often.
Luisa...
Luisa, come and see me.
Just for a short while.
- When are you starting the film?
- I don't know.
Let me talk to Luisa, please.
And you?
I'm in love with you, Marcello.
Since when?
Hello sir!
My dear friends...
Let's have fun!
We are all smart people.
- How are you?
- Good. And you?
- It has been quite a while... years!
- Unfortunately yes, my dear.
Thank you! I got it.
You want to know about
my political affiliation.
Why don't you tell us what you'd
be capable of doing for an interview.
- You wish I'd write that for you?
- Oh, how awful.
I don't really remember.
How can I answer?
I'm a bit confused.
Can we end it here?
Marcello?
Steiner!
And yet...
Now I am really confounded.
This tower in the way...
Who knows why things
went that way.
Marcello, the cigarette, please.
I have forgotten about it.
- I don't want to go upstairs.
- It's the rule.
- And the rule is the rule.
- But Guido...
What did you do?
What did you do,
you crazy fool?
Please pardon the intrusion,
Your Eminence.
But my producer is restless,
perhaps he's right...
Why does Anita need the dogs?
She is wonderful,
she looks like a gladiator.
You want to make love here?
Come on, make up something.
I have one thousand,
two thousand ideas.
I can keep you locked in here
for a week without boring you.
But you have to do everything I say.
You are right, you know?
There's no role in the film.
There isn't even a film.
There isn't anything anywhere.
Put the horse on the table
and her on the ground.
What has Marcello said?
Come and stand on the table.
This is the art I prefer,
the one that will be needed tomorrow.
A clear, precise art...
...without rhetoric, that doesn't lie,
that isn't flattering.
Now I have a job that I don't like,
but I often think about tomorrow.
- Yes, hello, thanks.
- I called you twice. Where were you?
I know. I'm sorry.
I was up in the production office.
We're working.
How are you?
A man who accepts to live like this
is a finished man,
he's nothing but a worm!
I don't believe in your aggressive,
sticky, maternal love!
I don't want it! I have no use for it!
You are always beautiful, Anita.
I can't spend my life calling you
on the phone!
I want to work in peace!
I don't know!
Miss, could you please
shut off that music?
Yes... of course...
You arrived just in time,
you know?
Why do you smile like that?
It was wonderful.
I'll enquire about it.
What he wrote was all true.
Come back here, you sick man.
- Come back.
- My mother is giving me the money.
- Nico.
- Marcellino!
- Bad boy Marcellino!
- How are you?
- Where are you going?
- To my fiancé’s castle...
...in Bassano di Sutri.
- Why don't you take me?
What do you want me to do?
I am working.
Now I bet she brings up
her husband again.
You don't think so?
You'll see, old Snaporaz.
I don't understand,
I can't hear.
- Well?
- I had to tell you.
And you did.
- Do you want me to ask her to dance?
- Yes, ask her.
Dear friends, there's just one truth.
It took me forty years to smoke
three packets of cigarettes a day
and now I am throwing away
everything.
I was friends with Steiner
but we didn't see each other often.
I don't know anything.
I really don't know anything.
So, dear Pippo... bye.
- Amelia, at least give me a little kiss!
- Yes.
Good evening, Maddalena.
How are you? Alone?
- Would you like to dance?
- No.
Is Maddalena with you?
Personally, I like Rome very much.
It's sort of a moderate, tranquil
jungle where one can hide well.
I would like to perform a small
trick in honour of our guest.
Mandrake's stick,
my order is immediate:
make the good old times
come back.
Let's say you are purity itself.
That you are spontaneity.
But what the hell does it mean
to be really honest?
Didn't you hear
what the Falcaccio said?
"It's time to set symbols aside, the
echoing of purity, innocence, escape."
I have to inform the public, it's my job.
After all,
it's just a little publicity.
You call that publicity? You got her
in trouble with her husband.
Do I worry about your being cuckolded?
You're not a journalist.
So, let's wrap it up this way:
Thank you
and see you next time.
It's cold here.
You are nice but the place isn't...