This way, Adele...
I'll take her out, Madam.
When are you showing "The Vale
of Love" with Gary Cooper?
Next week, my love.
Thanks a lot.
When can your little prince
sleep with you?
You'll get my purse over your head!
Such behaviour!
Get lost, Giudizio.
It was beautiful!
I had a good cry!
Open up, good lord!
18...
- 18?
- Campari!
- Aldina, wanna know who it was?
- We know. It was Campari
I met him in the race at Monza.
Lallo!
Watch out, Lallo!
Well done, Lallo!
- What is it, Lallo?
- An ear!
Look, an ear!
Where's Ronald Colman?
I don't see him.
Gradisca!
Hurray for Gradisca!
Where are all these people going?
Where are they going
with hearts pounding?
Watermelon!
Ice creams!
Today is a very important day
for our country, for the fatherland.
Come on, we're off!
Against the palate,
like this.
And then spit it out.
Try!
"There will come a day...
"when a renewed Italy
"will take to the field of battle
on her own behalf
"and not to defend her soil..."
This is the Rubicon...
The river that Julius Caesar crossed
and said...
Take your shoes off...
Shoes off!
And let's cross it together.
- To Rome!
One, two, three, four...
five, six, seven, eight....
These youth are sturdy as rock.
I agree.
One, two, three...
four, five, six, seven...
Hail Duce!
- Who locked the gate?
- I did.
- Why?
- You know why.
Unlock it.
Listen to the racket they've been
making in the piazza all day.
Open up.
I have business to take care of.
Nothing doing.
You're staying at home.
Take off this stuff!
If I want to be a widow, I'll
strangle you with your neckerchief!
Look!
Think I'm scared
of those black-shirted lice?
Give me the key.
Give me the key!
Miranda!
Damn it all!
Why is it that
whenever there's a f*****g rally,
she locks me in?
This is the last straw!
Ninety-nine per cent
of the population are party members.
We have 1,200 Young Fascist boys,
3,000 Young Fascist girls....
Our Fascist hearts beat as one,
but we should speed up the works
on the seafront.
This marvellous enthusiasm makes us
young and yet so old at the same time.
Young, because Fascism
has rejuvenated our blood
with glowing ideals
from ancient times.
All I can say is
Mussolini's got two balls this big!
Hey!
He's up there!
The fascist shit, his head is split
Crossed the Rubicon one day
and lost his balls along the way
Children, do you like Mussolini?
Julius Caesar salutes
with his hand...
Don't be an arsehole,
go and see Mom.
Do you think I am mad?
Stay calm!
Get your lottery tickets here.
Dragoni Hotel!
Pictures of the city of cinema,
which, for its perfect
facilities and services,
and for its impressive buildings
and studios
among which 9 perfectly isolated
stage theatres from outside noise,
has become a model in its own rights.
Don't laugh!
Step, hip...
Ladies, gentleman, comrades...
Cinema is young.
We were born
just after silent films.
We have witnessed
the triumph of sound.
We will witness the triumph
of colour.
Enough!
Stop!
Cesare, I was thinking...
What?
Why don't you stuff it up your arse?
- What do you want?
- Who is it? Who is it?
Do you think
there will be a war?
- Want to see the little granny?
- Sure. That's why I came.
Follow me.
She's littler than us kids.
I refuse to believe that the people
of Great Britain, always friends,
feel it their duty to lead Europe
into a catastrophe...
by defending an African nation.
The resemblance is frightening.
Universally branded and without
the shadow of any kind of civilization
against this nation of heroes,
artists, poets, saints, navigators...
..a resolute hostile attitude.
- Yes, let's go...
Yes, let's go...
Hottie!
My love! My angel!
Golden bum!
Isn't this the siren?
There's the alarm.
The audience must reach
the air-raid shelter
at street number 104.
Whose is the baby?
Who gave me this child?
Stay there.
Light!
Attilio!
Want to come and rest at mine?
My hotel is close.
They won't bomb us
as long as the Pope's in Rome.
Good night, Anita.
You might as well say good morning.
- What's that booming?
- They're bombs!
Help me!
They are bombing us!
Help!
Second air raid on Rome
covered by our cameramen.
The war hurricane hits also the homes
in the Prenestino, Casilino, Appio,
San Lorenzo, Pta Maggiore districts...
The city is covered
by a blanket of death.
For the fifth time the anniversary
of the Italian Republic:
the parade starts in the sky.
The applauses are silenced
by a fanfare.
Honourable colleagues,
the Chamber of Deputies
has instructed us
to investigate and gain
statistical, economic, legislative
information
for the war against poverty.
In fact, everybody knows
that poverty is a problem,
but few know
its most distressing side.
At a stone's throw from the Coliseum
there was the Domus Aurea,
a luxurious imperial dwelling.
Now its ruins are a shelter
for the refugees.
Once again the stone cubicles
are beds for the offspring of man.
Sometimes what is temporary
becomes final
and those who had to live
in these houses for a few month
ended up with staying for years.
Madam...
Why did you move
to the suburbs?
- Where did you use to live?
- In San Lorenzo.
- You moved because of the bombings?
- Yes.
Would you like a new house?
You bet I would like one.
I've ben sleeping for 18 years
in a disgusting two bed room.
They're giving us  a home.
Yes, a home.
They've been saying it for ages.
- I applied two years ago...
- Good morning, sir.
Good morning.
Thank god you are here.
My nane is Antonio Scioni.
I applied for a home
14 months ago.
Rome is growing.
New districts are built
on the suburbian meadows.
And yet shacks like this one
seemed a feat years ago
when they replaced even more
makeshift dwellings.
This is the new Tormancia,
a suburb of Rome,
its no longer means "bad life".
The people in Primavalle
are celebrating.
You will have a home.
Entire districts are rising
in the suburbs
designed with rational modern criteria
and bound to host decently
and comfortably
a great deal of homeless people.
It's all new, all renovated:
bridges, arches, viaducts...
It's started and it runs fast
our rebirth.
We are building stone by stone
this Italy ground by war.
Workers...
Workers from the plain...
- What's wrong with this car?
- Why are you stopping?
Open the bonnet.
Hey, they're coming.
We were joking.
Run!
- What happened?
- Alberto! Riccardo!
I was sleeping.
I was them.
I was asleep. I am a socialist.
The giving a new destination
to the Universal Exhibition in Rome.
These buildings will become a model
of model city-planning and culture.
Silence will cease in these places.
Marcello?
What do I have to do now.
Put the horse on the table
and the heron the ground.
Come here and stand on the table.
I'm coming.
Shall I pick you up at 8 pm?
- You are playing difficult to catch.
- I'm working.
Rome is an extraordinary city
and it is understandable that and
extraordinary world such as cinema
has chosen as its capital
this city,
which has seen so many
extraordinary events and things.
Postwar Italian cinema
is a worldwide phenomenon.
Our film industry is thriving.
Belinda Lee is arriving from London.
And here's BB
followed by Rock Hudson.
The glasses!
The diva is accompanied through customs.
Her fans are waiting to welcome her.
You look so fresh.
- Your friends are ready to attack.
- Marcello, where are you going?
- Miss Maddalena!
- Please, leave me alone tonight.
Welcome back. Here she is.
More photogenic than a star!
Every night the same story.
Don't they ever get bored?
Paparazzo, enough!
She'll eat you alive!
You should be used to it by now.
You're a public figure.
Marcello, where are you going?
Tell us where you are taking her.
The festival has ended.
There are many
useless controversies:
Wilma will have to make do
with rock 'n roll.
No latin or maths:
this is what youth studies today.
Ruggero?
Ruggero, are you serious?
You're not a sport.
You don't deserve a woman like this.
And now, Nadia, take off the stole!
Together with films that keep
the quality of Italian films very high,
other films relied on sexual
or porn innuendoes.
I wish to repeat
that gratuitous volgarity,
continuous offence to public decency,
pornography for its own sake
cannot and will not
from now on tolareted.
Shame on you!
It's a deadly sin.
I cannot believe it,
it's not possible.
Good morning.
In the glory of St Peter the Second
Ecumenical Council has started.
3000 bishops from everywhere reach
the greatest temple of Christianity.
Once again from the TV cameras
in Piazza San Pietro
the believers will see
the Saint Father's blessing figure
sent through those waves,
which have something spiritual.
Here they are!
Go as high as you can.
As soon as they get to the tree,
get a nice dolly shot.
Silence!
The Madonna said that if you don't
build a church she won't come anymore.
Good night! Go home!
Listen, I see that you have
a wonderful Morandi.
Yes...
He's my favourite painter.
The objects are flooded
with a wistful light
and yet painted with such
a detachment, precision, rigor...
President Gronchi inaugurates
the 8th Rome Quadriennale.
This is the map of the 30th Venice
Biennale which opened in these days.
Figurative and abstract art
are now juxtaposed.
And critics will express
their opinion.
..I've been paying everything
for month.
If you don't make the film,
I'll ruin you.
What's wrong in your life,
Mr. Dammit?
Is it true you have done
the most menial obs?
The war between TV and cinema
becomes tougher mand tougher.
The Italian TV
has hit the bull's eye.
The stake is 2 million and 560 thousand
lire.
I want to know if you want
to leave or double.
Let's find another hard sound
and with the print fonts
let's he how we can  match it
with an animal name.
Think it over for awhile.
Repeat this horizontal movement
of the eyes...
Look, Madam!
Look what Elisabetta is doing.
You mustn't move the head,
ust the eyes,
Wait a minute!
Like this.
Faster and faster.
With an excavator today
and some ground tomorrow
that's how new roads
are built in Italy.
Silently the Motorway of the Sun
is becoming a reality.
When the great plan of roads
and motorwways will be realized
our country will have
a great communication network.
- Overtake, Marcello.
- Stop it.
Don't you see there's a traffic jam?
Overtake.
Run him over.
Thee last hectic works in Rome,
which is now ready to host people
from all over the world
who are coming for
the 17th Olympic Games.
The first four road tunnels
are opening
and their convenience and usefulness
have already turned out to be great,
In the Capitol Square a new chapter
of the marathon legend is beginning.
At mile 12 only two runners
are leading.
And the second is Abebe Biikila.
For them the gates of the city
are lighting up?
When will all the underground
network be finished?
"Underground" for Rome
is  bad word.
A word full of question marks.
Here where the first underground
station will be built,
we understand why.
The drill has found
new archeological exhibits.
Stop the drill!
Who am I?
Good morning.
Do you live here?
So far, yes.
We celebrated a wedding yesterday.
The crickets were our orcherstra.
In Trinita' dei Monti the stairway and
the fountain are invaded by hippies.
They come from Italy and broad
and camp here.
Citizens are outraged,
the police sometimes intervene
but these unique champions
of the protest are irremovable.
These disenchanted youths
hug together like puppies,
like chicks.
Love isn't...
Clear the square.
Why who are we bothering?
Clear! Clear!
I'm not bothering anyone:
you cannot beat me!
Dear Madam, these are dirty vagrants.
Their only thought
is to make love.
Don't be scared: they aren't
doing anything to them.
Music is a means
of exploitation!
Worse than in the factory!
#We are many
#We are more than half
#And we have always been
#part of mankind
#We are many
#We are more than half
#Amd we don't count anything
#in this society
Sisters, watch out, a man,
a male haunts us
He listens to our conversations
Steals our words
Records our speeches
and broadcasts them reditied
He is spying us.
We must stop him,
look for him, block him.
Throw him out.
Sorry...
There he is,
it's him.
Look, evertything is falling.
Help!
Berzot didn't play well.
My heart is bursting.
Madam, there aren't
any players today in Italy.
All they want is money.
I want a picture with Gullit.
Me and Gullit.
Is it OK here?
Come on!
Silvio Berlusconi, from Milan,
aged 49.
Classical examples of
self-made man.
Critics have objections on the value
of his TV programmes.
But he answers convinced
that they have cultural value.
We are happy to say goodbye with
our password: Spritz Sugo.
And life becomes a Paciugo.
Let's welcome, by applauding him,
a men who's really in love.
It's the retreat sign,
let's go.
TV addicted!
Here are the infamous spots
interrupting systematically
shows, news programmes and films.
Private televisions broadcast them
inceessantly.
The war has been declared from cinema
to private TVs,
It's dawn.
They will attack noww.
There they are.
It's them.
- Did you like it?
- Yes, very good.
- How dit it go?
- How do I know.
He siad, "Stop."
- Do we have to come back tomorrow?
- I have just told you it's over.
Merry Christmas!
Enough now!
Long live, gnocchi!
Mandrakes's stick
my order is immediate
Make the good old days come back!
Can you see studio 5
from that height?
Maurizio, answer me!
Heres studio 5!
It's wonderful from up here.
We can also see the aqueduct.
And the Tuscolana Road.
But everything is trembling.
Now you should focus
on the sound.
The megaphone
isn't working anymore.
The batteries are dead.
Take 1!