One thing is building
a cinema museum...
There is already one in Italy
and it is excellent.
Something else is creating a museum
dedicated to one figure, an auteur.
In this case,
we need to plan carefully
the textual and poetical
organization of this auteur.
In Fellini's case,
I think it's very clear.
Fellini started with
a very well organized textuality:
His films that had
a beginning and an ending.
But his later films no longer
contained the word "ending".
These films generally consisted
of fragments.
When I say fragments
I mean fragments
that didn't dream their totality,
something that often
is the case with fragments.
These "totalities"
were marked by the fact
they lacked the word "ending".
And the lack of the word "ending"
in Fellini's case
was, at the same time, an invitation
perhaps to continue
or perhaps to start all over again.
This specific nature of Fellini's work
is important for a museum.
In my opinion a museum isn't
a place where you learn,
where you organize texts with
a beginning, the first Fellini,
a development,
Fellini after "La dolce vita",
the ending,
Fellini's last film.
We don't necessarily employ
an historical criterion.
But not even...
a personal one.
This is a museum that must
reflect the singularity
that characterizes Fellini:
his more and more fragmented editing,
which in the end
rightly lacks the word "ending".
On the other hand, this
is the answer to a question,
which is peculiar
to moving arts...
which also include theatre,
vaudeville and circus,
that is how to divide
the representation
of the museum
and, in the meantime,
the type of reading,
implied for the visitor.
Therefore I would like to remind you
that the idea of going to
a Fellinian museum
to watch a Fellini film,
or maybe all his films
is unthinkable for two reasons:
first of all, nowadays museums
aren't generally
organized that way.
And one must stay away
of this type of organization.
Secondly there is the length
of perception...
I mean the perception of
the work of art
which entails the issue
of consumption units
as far as watching
and listening is concerned.
So...
Let's think about literature...
Or even about painting.
It's totally normal in the criticism
and teaching of literature
to publish collections.
In collections
you do not find the entire works,
but only parts of it.
I don't find at all strange
showing just one fragment
by Fellini.
I know very well that
his fragments are organized
in a way that gives
a certain rhythm
to the film.
But this doesn't prevent us,
with an educational purpose,
which is typical of museums,
from doing something similar.
For instance, no one would ask
anybody who wants to visit
a museum on Dante
to read beforehand
all the "Divine Comedy".
And maybe to study the episode
about Francesca from Rimini.
I believe
the same can be done with cinema,
that is taking some elements
and episode considered fundamental
and isolating them.
On the other hand,
Fellini gave permission
the day he titled one of his works
"Otto e mezzo" (eight and a half).
What is this half?
As we know....
"Toby Dammit" lasts 40 minutes
and not the usual
90-minute length.
This idea that some episodes
can be isolated
with criteria based on criticism
is one of the reasons why,
besides the natural fragmentation
of Fellini's works,
on an educational level,
some parts can be isolated
some elements can be isolated,
which can be created
with different criteria.
In any case the museum
must think
about how
it can create its own reader
and give them
specific reading times.
In my opinion among these times,
there is the idea
of constructing elements
that can exemplify situations.
The idea is
that a museum should offer,
in some specific areas,
a few small mind references
using things that we believe
can exemplify.
A museum is a place
where properties are exemplified.
From this perspective
surely the last problem is
to see the entire work of art.
This is unthinkable.
For this there are dedicated spaces.
Instead we need to take samples
with the intent of illustrating.
In Fellini's case
we are particularly lucky,
as is work is made of fragments
that we can isolate some.
This is an inner criterion of the work.
From the standpoint of criticism
we can take from the text,
not necessarily following
the fragment criterion,
small elements exemplifying
some properties
that we want to highlight.
I would like to say something
about one of these properties.
This is the relation between
"The Book of Dreams"
and Fellini's texts.
So...
"The Book of Dreams"
is very ingenuous and specific.
And it is very likely that
for many of his films
to some extent...
dream was...
the pretext...
in the strong meaning
of the word "text".
The written and visual pretext
which was subsequently transposed,
meaning translated
into the specific language of cinema
with music and a certain type
of spatial organization.
The problem of the daytime
treatment of dream
of which Fellini was one
of the greatest masters
should be looked at more carefully.
The museum is also where
this shift should be discussed:
The shift between...
on the one hand,
the dream dimension
and on the other
its visual transcription
without reductionism.
Without mentioning its dream source,
so to speak.
In fact, the final text,
the one that somehow
in a spectacular way
in "La città delle donne"
was realized…
This final text
has rewritten dream…
to a certain extent
it completely redefined it.
The idea of showing how
dreams were first rewritten
through drawn images
and written texts
and then transformed,
this becomes, I would say,
another educational,
and also creative moment
in the museum.
Naturally...
every museum should
supply instructions.
But in the case of cinema
this is fundamental.
Not only for the large quantity
of images there is today,
within which both Fellini's cinema
and the museum are located.
These are images
in a universe of images.
Therefore, instructions
are particularly necessary.
Otherwise these images
end up with disappearing
in the incredible quantity of images
to which we are exposed.
So what are these features?
Surely the fact that
they are moving images.
And this is very important
compared to how museums
usually treat...
For instance...
a photography show.
The idea of moving images
is particularly important
as it is to some extent
the way in which a museum
should address
not with the old "medium"
of the representative museum,
which we picture with images
and texts attached to walls
or paintings on the wall,
but that has to answer
with other moving images.
This idea of the translation
of images
is the fundamental point
that should...
to which visitors should be exposed.
Visitors will surely
come to see Fellini,
but they must be instructed
that this is a place where
Fellini's work is translated
by the staging
of the specific images
by Studio Azzurro.
Moreover, in this case
we find ourselves
before a different quality
of the images.
How can I say...
of their expression.
These are images
from new technologies.
It is clear that
the shift from technology
to technology
requires instructions.
This also means that
the museum
has an enormous responsibility.
It doesn't just illustrate something
as we once said.
But it has to translate something.
This translation, which isn't
a translation in the literal sense:
from word to word,
but from a type of image
to another type of image,
from images made in a certain way
to images made with new technologies.
Clearly they expose visitors
to types of experience
that are very different.
The other thing is the need
in this translation,
which is typical of the dissemination
role characterizing museums...
In this case, though,
dissemination is not possible
if it betrays the nature of...
the work of art.
It's impossible to transform a Fellini
film into a series of photographs
of his characters
or of frames from his films.
To some extent this is
a retranslation...
with a medium
which is previous to cinema.
The other need is for the translation
not only to disseminate knowledge
but also to recreate Fellini's work.
I mean, to some extent,
Studio Azzurro is responsible
for being not only the dissemination
of Fellini's discourse,
something that visitors could expect,
but also for rewriting,
for reimagining Fellini's discourse,
which can have its independent quality
from a point of view of
the style and the beauty.
As Fellini rightly said,
it's not just his work…
Fellini
is something like Fellinism,
the adjective "Fellinian",
as Fellini stressed.
Fellini is also all the conversations,
texts, images, people
that surrounded him
and of which the museum
shouldn’t get rid.
I believe they are part of Fellini
and they seeped deeply
into his work.
And exited from his work
in the form of words, styles
life styles...
a way which is Fellinian.
How does the museum
relate to this aura...
of chats
and gossip
of information about life styles
that cinema has represented?
How does the museum tackle
the issue of the Fellinian life style,
the one he,
willingly or not, proposed
and to which is also partly due
his reputation?
I think there two ways
of doing it.
One is studying it
and maybe it would be interesting
if the museum became
a place of proposition,
not only of research on
the quality and variety of his work.
But also on the way
how cinema as a medium
succeeded in creating this sort
of textual semiotic universe
that surrounds the work
and the figure of Fellini.
How do we go about it?
I believe that...
there is a strategy
from this point of view:
that is, witnesses.
In Fellini's case
most of the people interviewed
rarely describe episodes
about Fellini's work,
they tell us about episodes
of his life,
of the life...
of the Hollywood moment
in Cinecittà,
of personal relationships....
I think this should
be taken into account.
And the museum should be
a place of promotion
o the reconstruction of the memory
of a specific life style.