And now dear friends,
if you allow me,
I would like to show you
a small trick
to celebrate our beloved host.
Mandrake's stick...
To who my order may concern,
make the good old days return.
Maya, let's make these bores
have a bit of fun.
Signora, mi permetta
Allow me, Madam.
Are you ready, Maya?
What am I holding?
A velvet handbag.
A white handkerchief.
A red handkerchief.
- No drugs, I hope.
- No, it's aspirin.
- A purse.
- Is there any money in it?
2,725 lire.
Bravo!
Ladies and gentlemen,
you're thinking, "What a trickster."
Well, sorry to disappoint you,
but there's no trick.
No coincidence.
It's an exceptional example
of magnetic fields and telepathy.
I'll be there in a second.
You're famous now.
Cut it out.
Just tell me what's your trick?
Well, it's partly a trick,
but part of it is real.
- I don't know how, but it happens.
- Can you transmit anything?
Anything. Except for her to get lost.
- Do you want to try?
- Yes. Wait.
I bet now, with you, it won't work.
Can you repeat?
You shut up and eat your ice-cream.
It's the estimate for the spaceship.
I need to talk to you later,
face to face,
I'm at the end of my rope.
This is a madhouse!
Guido!
What does that mean?