Wait...
Laugh, laugh!
Go, Menicuccio.
One,two...
three, four!
One, two...
three, four.
Stop, enough!
What has happened?
Ready? Let's go.
No, no, no.
Ready?
Roll! Go!
Hold my hand.
Try to be natural.
Do you believe in these things?
You know you are guided by
a spirit from the afterlife.
I have always told you.
But today you're a bit unhappy,
a frame in the film
won't satisfy you.
- Let me see something.
- Please.
Let's see what happens.
- Who would you like to become?
- I want to be an actor.
- Like Cagliostro?
- Do something big.
Try to wave "Ciao."
Slower, darling.
Really slow.
One, two, three...
And then come back.
Come back very slowly.
Let's try again.
And then look here...
- I need to look where you are.
- Yes.
When Gianni is here, look at
my hand near his face.
Look at the rose hedge.
Flowers make those who love them
very grateful.
Look up.
She must be full of love,
to give away so much.
Good...
Go, Gianni.
Keep looking at my hand.
Good...
Go, Menicuccio.
Un uomo che si prostituisce.
Che si vende alle donne
anche se preferirebbe gli uomini...
E cosa si può dire di Gitone?
Un giorno ha indossato
una stola da donna.
L'aveva convinto sua madre.
Vieni, Hiram.
Vieni, Martino.
Bacia Martino...
Bacia Hiram, a sinistra.
Coricati, Hiram.
Guarda Martino.
Vai con le mani.
Accarezza Martino.
Guardalo, Martino.
Coricati, Martino.
Accarezzalo, Hiram.
As disorderly as you can.
The crazier you can
as if you were electrified.
Throw your arms and legs
everywhere.
Ready?
Come here,
I need to give you something.
No, when things start.
I come from a very ancient family
of actors and wizards
and, as I told you, I am a wizard.
Fellini is a wizard, too.
During the film I wanted to send him
my fluid, but he rejected it.
He even sent me his own
to hypnotize me.
In other words, to make me
become Grandpa.
While we were shooting
the scene in the fog,
when I am lost and scared,
Fellini kept screaming...
"Janigro you can't see a thing."