Bats!
- Eugenio, how stupid.
- Cristina makes me laugh.
It isn't true.
- Are you working?
- Yes.
Dimmi chi sei.
Who do you want
to communicate with?
I feel some energy...
Countess, keep the contact.
Don't laugh!
I'm not laughing.
Why don't you leave me alone?
Please, go away.
- Call Sister Edvige!
- Who is she?
It's a nun that in the summer,
walks around here...
...carrying her head on a dish.
- Yeah, right.
She is drunk.
Blow out the candles!
Who are you?
Who do you want to communicate with?
Giulio, it's a message for you.
Where are you?
Sometimes I think,
"There must be a place in the world
"where there's a hole, an opening,
to the other side?"
In Paris, the Marquise D'Ufre's salon
was the one most sought after,
by every outstanding person
of art and culture.
I met Count Saint-Germain,
a magician who practiced occultism,
who I considered without scruples.
I am in contact
with the Queen of Saba.
Oh, how kind!
She has returned to us.
What is the water that does not
come from the rocks,
that does not fall from the sky,
that does not come from the earth?
Answer, the sweat of a horse.
They are the enigmas of Salomon.
That is his answer to the queen.