Gina!
Where am I?
It looks as I am nowhere.
If death is like this...
it's not that nice.
Everything had disappeared...
People, trees,
birds in the sky, wine.
Up yours!
Dino!
I can't even find my home.
Where am I?
Where are you, my love?
Why?
I will meet Horace,
Dante,
I will converse with Petrarch,
with Ariosto,
and with you,
Torquato Tasso,
My tender friend whose verses come to
my mind in this supreme moment.
Oh Death,
oh quiet in every human state.
Hey!
The great Mouna!
The queen of whales!
Jonas' Leviathan!
Everyone can enter.
The stomach is still warm.
A female whale. Look at its
mouth, inviting you to go inside.
Are you afraid?
He who does not enter into its
stomach will not find the treasure.
So says the ancient Book of Wisdom.
"Come and you will see inside
its throat and farther down,
in the stomach
of the great Mouna...
The Mouna is a door
that leads who knows where...
Ivo Salvini...