I'm so angry I would cry?
It's disgusting, a madhouse, a circus,
the dwarfs, the transvestites...
And then what's this admiral?
I didn't understand.
They say he'll be acting with us.
Us, who?
Pippo did not come.
I'm crazy for pizza.
He's not here yet!
Who will I dance with, then?
He's no fool! I shouldn't
have let you persuade me.
I knew I shouldn't have come.
I might have run away tonight,
you know.
Olive oil.
Think about it.
I’m leaving everything and
they'll have to go on without me!
And how is he doing?
Very well!
You look a little pale. How come?
See, the hotel is right here.
You are everything...
Do you know you are everything?
You are the first woman
in the first day of creation.
You are the mother,
the sister, the lover, the friend...
the angel, the devil,
the earth, the house.
That's what you are...
the house.
Good evening, Madam.
Sir...
I would like to recommend...
consommé d'Orléans,
potage soissonnais
o crêpes beurrés.
Bouchée à la gauloise...
Dartois à la reine...
Marmite lyonnaise.
Soupe Colbert...
Gelée de bouillon...
Bouillon royale.
Crêpe Valesca-à-la sauce supreme...
Rigatoni!
And like an echo we answer:
Barilla!
Barilla you make me always feel...
firm to the bite.
Say bye from me to everyone.
Goodnight!
"The most delicious pasta
in the world."
"Fulvio Lombardoni Pasta."
Put your hand on the tap!
Now, the sauce!
Well done!
The winter crumble pie!
10 ounces of corn flour.
10 ounces of butter
and beaten eggs.
I have dreamt my poor mum...
Good!
She said I would win
a lot of money.
Yes, you have won 20 million lire.
Say hello to the mayor.
Quick, the time is almost over!
Go, go, go!
We have just awarded
someone who deserves it
and now we are glad to say goodbye
with our password:
Spritzsugo
and life becomes a "paciugo".
- "Till the next show!"
- Damn!
Is it any good?
Hey, I've asked you if it's good.
Sure! What makes you
think it isn't?
Meat costs 8 lire per kilo.
What's this world coming to?
Who knows?
They have found out
how to make money.
#Sailor moon,
#love is beautiful but...
We have brought them from home.
What do you want, urchin?
Stay seated!
And then we are going to eat
in Ostia.
Where did you fetch the chicken from?
May you be damned!
It's like before
Do you think I am stupid?
Hey come here, you Good for nothing!
Do you think we are waiting for you?
Marcello!
Are you sure you haven't
called the wrong number?
Listen Maddalena,
can I bring someone?
- Someone?
- Who's calling her in the night?