Camera! Action! Stop!
I am considered
an autobiographical director
and I must say that...
My autobiography
is totally invented.
Therefore...
My most precise memories
are those I have put....
in my films.
The memories of the inventions
in the film.
No, I'm not helped by a good memory.
In fact, if I were to think back...
to the first years of my life
or to my childhood and adolescence...
It can't go any faster.
..I don't remember
any particular event.
A long and sleepy brewing...
to find myself
inside a studio one day...
to wake up and invent
a childhood, an adolescence...
memories that in the end
were all made up.
This question
about the first years in my life
makes me very uncomfortable.
To me it's like a long motionless day.
Honestly, my true autobiography,
my true memories
begin on the day
I first entered a studio
and I started saying,
"Camera! Action! Stop!"
Repeat with me, "One, two..."
Whispering...
When as child, I saw a circus
for the first time
I had the same emotions as a child
who wants to become a priest
upon entering a church
during Elevation.
No, one, two, three, four...
I, instead, without reaching
such a zealous image
of a life made of privation
and sacrifice,
I saw a sort of Annunciation.
Wait, you are almost there.
The first time I saw clowns,
to me the seemed the ambassadors
announcing...
a life, a career, a calling
to which I couldn't say no.
Besides the rhetoric of this image,
it was really like this.
The clowns
I was approached by the first time
with their grotesque masks...
They refer to,
in an unmistakable way…
as Saint Paul in Damascus,
I had the same revelation
of my profession,
of my life.
What happened?
Ready? Let's go!
I have been to a boarding school
run by priests.
They were called "Carissimi"
they wore a white collar.
I made Anita Ekberg wears
that same collar in "La dolce vita".
She is dressed like
those ancient priests.
This school was in Fano.
There was an age from 8 to 14
when you couldn't escape
boarding school.
Sarghina was,
as I tell in "Otto e mezzo",
the first overwhelming apparition
of pure sex.
OK!
At the time all the children
were dressed in the same suit
with gold buttons...
We gave her all our buttons.
We were very young: 7 or 8,
and couldn't expect anything else...
she had big bouncy boobs
and did a boisterous dance
with her big bottom.
I was traumatized.
I was in the car with a lady,
who was driving and talking to me,
she was getting things off her chest,
I didn't understand much.
She was speaking about a divorce,
and was even crying.
She was driving a beautiful
convertible car.
I didn't understand much and showed
my sympathy through gestures.
I was looking at the skyline
and the skyscrapers.
I was leaning out from the window.
Then someone knocked on my head.
Next to us there was another
car with two policemen inside.
They told us to pull over.
Neither I nor the lady
had a driving licence.
And she didn't even have ID on her.
Really?
I said that my documents
were at the hotel.
I don't remember what hotel.
And I said my name.
There was a policeman
of Italian origin.
He recognized me as the director.
He said,
"That Fellini who made 'La strada'?'
I said yes and he said...
"That's me".
He asked me to sing
Gelsomina's trumpet tune.
I had to do...
a musical improvisation.
He hugged me and he made
the motorbikes escort me to the hotel
as if I were the president
of the United States.
A very nice gesture,
a very nice way Americans
have to show their admiration
towards show business people.
Stop!
For me it's OK this way:
chalk white, a big mozzarella.
He will play Emperor Commodus.
Caterina, is your ankle
feeling any better?
Why are your eyes always red?
Put some drops in your eyes.
I have a mortifying statement
to make.
Going to the cinema isn't something
that comes to my mind.
It's a sort of rite or habit
that stopped to exist when I started
making films myself.
Maybe psychoanalysis
can explain
my lack of interest.