Quick with the make-up!
- Is the first camera ready?
- Ready!
- Is the second ready?
Everyone in their place!
Let's start!
Further back the Bedouins!
- Sir, your helmet.
- Thank you.
The megaphone?
Everyone to their position!
Take the sunshades away!
Can I start?!
Stop! That's enough!
Stop!
Stay like that!
Ready!
Who is that cretin?
Away!
- You go away!
- Leave!
- Go away, idiot!
Stop!
- Stop!
- Ready!
Stop! Go!
Take!
Do not laugh!
Now the beach was desert...
but we went to watch the sea anyway.
Saraghina!
If a man came and gave you
10,000 lire, would you bathe?
I would.
- Shall we go?
- Where?
To see Giudizio.
Saraghina...
Let's go, Riccardo.
You know who Leopoldo
looks like? The priest!
I want to tell you that
many of the people you met
saved themselves.
A seaplane has rescued
the survivors from lifeboat Aurora.
The lifeboat Stella del Nord
has miraculously reached Ancona.
Unfortunately, I have
no news from the others.
As far as I am concerned....
I have some great news to break...
Did you know that rhinos
give an excellent milk?
Fu Manchu!
Volpina!
Come here!
The wind has subsided.
Down there you see the pier.
Come and read Act IV to me.
Sir... Sergio...
- Where are you going?
- We'll find a place down there.
But it's dark down there.
Sir...
Come!
Are you afraid of me?
Leopoldo!
Where are you going?
I was joking.
What did you understand?
Come back, Leopoldo!
#I want to dance with you
#All night long like this
On the third day I went there
with my boat.
I whistled as usual.
The dolphin came out,
Put its head on the boat,
looked at me and said...
"Mummy!"
Oh come on!
Dolphins are very intelligent,
my dentist said that too.
Look how many there are.
Millions and millions
and millions of stars.
My goodness...
I wonder how all that junk
can stay stuck up there.
For us it's quite easy...
If I need to construct a building,
I get the bricks and the cement.
But up there...
where do I put the foundations?
They are not confetti.
Surprising, my darling.
Here it comes!
Dad! Dad!
The Rex!
Long live the Rex!
Once dead, we are a heap of dust.
If a bone is left,
we must watch out for the cat.
Go swimming, buy a horse
and go jumping.
But most importantly
tell your husband
to make love
more frequently.
Yes, I know, doctor.
Le prime settimane...
sono sempre molto difficili
perché tutti i fantasmi
che si avevano per la mente
devono materializzarsi
e diventare oggettivi.
I'm going to bathe, Sir.
Questa operazione magica...
Da Catherine la vita era felice.
A happy life reigned at Catherine's.
Il marito l'adorava.
Her husband adored her.
E i figli erano forti e laboriosi.
Her children were strong and diligent.
Tutti gli uomini del vicinato
All the men in the neighbourhood
la prendevano come esempio
set her as an example
per le mogli.
for their wives.
Giulietta!
Please, help me!
I am old.
Besides, it concerns you.
I caught him.
Hey!
Come down!
Come!
Help me.
Down for good.
Juliet, the lady over there
sent us this fruit basket.
Wasn't that nice!