She was the most beutiful woman
in the world.
A ducth woman who lived upstairs
from us when I was in high school.
Madam, let me help you,
I'll carry the bucket for you.
But I'm not a child anymore,
I'm a manager now,
an important,
respected, feared man.
Is there someone who can translate?
Yes, me.
She is saying that deep inside
you are still a child.
Doorman!
Exit slowly, Paolo.
Look at the lamp.
An expression that broke my heart.
Still now I feel like crying.
Why do you keep your lion
in the basement
humiliating it, debasing it?
Come on, don't make it cry.
Sometimes pride, haughtiness
and a certain level of aggressiveness
can make you feel safer.
For instance,
here is an abstract painting,
besides the evocative geometry
it lets you catch sight of
solid, rational structures,
which give you a feeling of order,
protection.
The same that Banca di Roma
can give you.
Follow my advice
and your night anxiety will disappear.
I like to think I have followed
a good piece of advice.
And from now on I hope
my nights will be peaceful.
I wish you the same.
Good night!
- What do you want?
- A packet of Nazionali.
- Let me help you, Miss.
- Keep away, you're no good.
What do you mean?
I can lift 80 kilos.
- I once lifted even my dad.
- You make me laugh.
Eat this rubbish yourselves.
Redhead, let me go.
Let me get away.
I didn't do anything!
Stop, infamous wardens!
We're about to enter my territory.
Let's steal another car.
My ears are freezing.
Well, this is what I call a sausage.
I want to tell you a secret,
I want to make my brother happy.
Donald Duck goes, "Quak, quak."
It's not Donald Duck, it's a penguin.
Penguin!
You look a bit stupid.
- Yes, I'm happy.
- Please.
A beautiful day, isn't it, Sir?
Glorious, I would say.
Quick, climb up.
Come up here.
Come on!
Look, the train is coming.
Now that I've decided to tell
my wife everything.
Help!
The risk is very serious,
we mustn't waste time.
And the means of escape is
not what the lady suggests.
You should become the driver
and slow down in time
to avoid catastrophe.
Dear friend, the wheel of our life
is in our hands.
Banca di Roma can help you
to find the right way.
What about the money?
I don't deal with financial issues,
but with psychological problems.
Banca di Roma takes care
of everything else.
Follow my advice and your night
anxiety will disappear.
I like to think I have followed
a good piece of advice.
And from now on I hope
my nights will be peaceful.
I wish you the same.
Good night!
Silvia!
What are you doing?
Marcello,
dobbiamo trovare del latte.
Darling, where do I find milk
at this time of night?
Da quella parte!
Silvia, where are you going
with that cat?
Rome is full of cats.
I will look...
Come here!
Stop!
Non qui, là.
What do you know?
Fulvio Lombardoni's zampone!
Come! Come!
Zampone and lentils
for everyone!
It's all free!
Come! Come!
To be honest, I don't know
why I have accepted.
Perhaps to make my grandchildren happy,
they have insisted so much.
Then this myth of television,
which fascinates us all.
Anyway, I'm here.
I've always loved risking.
I'm not the type of person
who draws back.
Pippo says that the real artist
is like a wolf.
When they hear
the call of the forest...
Hey, do you want to run me over?